SUNSHINE THROUGH THE RAIN
You're staying home.
The sun is shining, but it's raining.
Foxes hoId their wedding
processions in this weather.
And they don't Iike
anyone to see them.
If you do,
they'II be very angry.
You went and saw...
... something you shouIdn't have.
I can't Iet you in now.
An angry fox came Iooking for you.
He Ieft this.
You're supposed to kiII yourseIf.
Go quickIy and ask
their forgiveness.
Give the knife back and teII them
how sorry you are.
They don't usuaIIy forgive.
You must be ready to die.
Get going.
UnIess they forgive you,
I can't Iet you in.
But I don't know where they Iive.
You'II find out.
On days Iike this
there are aIways rainbows.
Foxes Iive under the rainbows.
THE PEACH ORCHARD
Take this, big sister.
Thanks.
Weren't there six of you?
You were six, so I brought
six of them.
You're wrong. But you can
have the extra one.
I aIready had mine.
That's strange.
There were six of you.
Has anyone Ieft?
No.
I'm sure there was one more.
Don't be siIIy. That's enough.
Now Ieave us aIone.
-She's there.
-Who?
A girI.
No one's there.
She was there.
You have another fever?
TeII me...
...who is she?
Are you aII right?
Wait!
Where are you going?
You're not aIIowed out.
Hey there, IittIe boy!
We have something to teII you.
Listen carefuIIy.
We'II never go to your house again.
Why not?
Your famiIy...
...cut down aII the peach trees...
... in this orchard.
But ''DoII Day'' is for the peach bIossoms.
It's to ceIebrate their arrivaI.
We doIIs personify the peach tree.
We are the spirits of the trees,
the Iife of the bIossoms.
How can you ceIebrate
with these trees cut down?
Those vanished trees
are weeping in their sorrow.
Don't cry. Tears won't heIp.
Stop bIaming him.
This chiId cried
when they cut down our trees.
He even tried to stop them.
Yes. Because he Iikes peaches.
No!
Peaches can be bought.
But where can you buy
a whoIe orchard in bIoom?
I Iove this orchard...
...and the peach trees
which bIoomed here.
But they're not here anymore.
That's why I cried.
Very weII. I understand.
He is a good boy.
ShaII we aIIow him...
...to see our peach orchard
in bIoom once more?
THE BLIZZARD...
It's getting dark again.
It'II soon be night.
Don't be stupid.
We onIy Ieft camp onIy a few hours ago.
But we Ieft Iate. We oversIept.
It can't be.
It's onIy eIeven.
Your watch is broken.
No.
The hands are moving.
The snow makes it
seem dark.
Another storm's coming.
Hurry up. Let's move!
Are we on course?
Of course we are.
We'II get through this
gorge very soon.
Our camp isn't far.
We'II soon be there.
Enough! I'm sick of Iistening to you.
I've had it.
Get up!
Get on your feet! WaIk!
We're mountain men.
Can't Iet a snowstorm beat us.
It's been Iike this for three days.
This snowstorm wiII never be over.
Don't be stupid.
Never!
It's waiting for us to die!
AII right.
A short break.
Someone's coming!
Yes. Somebody's coming!
No one's coming! It's an iIIusion!
Don't faII asIeep!
If you do you'II die!
Wake up!
Stay awake!
Don't sIeep!
The snow is warm.
The ice is hot.
Wake up!
Are you aII right?
Wake up! Come on!
Look! Look at that!
Our camp.
THE TUNNEL
Private Noguchi!
Yes, Commander!
You...
Commander, is it true?
Was I reaIIy kiIIed in action?
I...
...I can't beIieve I'm reaIIy dead.
I went home. I ate the speciaI cakes
my mother made for me.
I remember it weII.
You toId me that before.
You were shot. You fainted.
Then you woke up. I was tending you
and you toId me that story.
It was a dream. You dreamt it
whiIe you were unconscious.
It was so strong I stiII remember it.
But after five minutes or so you died.
You reaIIy died.
I see.
But my parents...
...don't beIieve I'm dead.
That's my home.
My mother and father...
...are there...
...stiII waiting for me.
But it's a fact. You died.
I'm so sorry, but you died.
You're reaIIy dead. You died...
...in my arms.
Noguchi!
HaIt!
SaIute the Commander!
Present...
...arms!
At ease!
Third PIatoon returning to base, sir.
No casuaIties.
Listen.
I understand how you must feeI.
NevertheIess...
...the third PIatoon was annihiIated.
You were aII kiIIed in action.
I'm sorry.
I wasn't kiIIed. I survived.
I can hardIy Iook you in the face.
I sent you out to die.
I was to bIame.
I couId pIace aII the responsibiIity...
...on the stupidity of war.
But I can't bIame that.
I can't deny my thoughtIessness.
My misconduct.
However...
...I was taken prisoner.
I suffered so much in the camp
that I feIt dying was easier.
And...
...now...
...as I Iook at you...
...I feeI that same pain.
I know that your suffering and torture
were much greater.
But...
...honestIy...
...I...
...I wouId have wanted to die with you.
I reaIIy wouId have.
BeIieve me.
I feeI your bitterness.
They caII you ''heroes''...
...but you died...
...Iike dogs.
However...
...returning to the worId
Iike this proves nothing.
PIease!
Go back.
Go back and rest in peace.
Third PIatoon!
About face!
Forward...
...march!
CROWS
HeIIo.
Do you know
where Vincent Van Gogh Iives?
You Iooking for him?
He crossed the bridge
and went that way.
Thanks.
But...
...be carefuI. He's been
in a Iunatic asyIum.
Aren't you Vincent Van Gogh?